08 - Non-Proliferation Treaty
NATO Archives Online
08 - Non-Proliferation Treaty
1963-1969
NPT
227 Items
NATO Archives Online Boulevard Léopold III NATO Headquarters Brussels Capital Belgium 1110 Email: nato.archives@hq.nato.int https://www.nato.int/cps/en/natolive/68238.htm
More NATO documents from this period are also available in the NATO Archives Reading Room, located in NATO HQ in Brussels, Belgium. More information can be found on the NATO Archives website (https://www.nato.int/archives).
Subject File - Non-Proliferation Treaty
The NPT was hailed as a landmark treaty, offering a solution to a complicated set of problems facing the world at the time. Prior to the NPT, more than 20 countries were actively seeking nuclear weapons. The NPT created a legal framework defining nuclear weapon possessor and non-possessor states, and providing the context for their cooperation on all three pillars.
The Treaty is founded on three pillars: non-proliferation; disarmament; and peaceful use of nuclear weapons. Many of the records focus on US-USSR negotiations on Articles I and II of the Treaty regarding stopping the spread of nuclear weapons, and talks about Article III, on safeguards.
published
NPT
NAO
These files highlight NATO’s role and involvement in the drafting, negotiating and eventual signature of the Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT). The Treaty was opened for signature on 1 July 1968, and came into force on 5 March 1970. NATO, as an organization, is not a formal party to the Treaty but all its member states are signatories.
NATO also was involved with the NPT to ensure that NATO’s existing nuclear sharing arrangements were fully compatible with Articles I and II of the Treaty.
The different volumes show NATO’s deep involvement in the Treaty, and their commitment at all levels to full implementation of the articles in the Treaty. Records show heads of state, ambassadors, and working-level officers discussing and reviewing key components of the Treaty and how the articles could impact individual Allies, European integration, global and regional safeguards, and NATO.
Some of the documents originate from the various delegations, especially the United States Mission to NATO. The US Mission kept Allies apprised on the progress of the negotiations bilaterally with the USSR, and Allies discussed negotiations in Geneva in the Eighteen Nation Disarmament Committee, which included 4 Allies. The US maintained the principle of no consultations with the Soviets on the NPT without consultation with Allies.
The file is a curated collection of material related to the NPT, and split by the archivists into three volumes: the Private Records, the Subject Files and the Related Materials. Within each volume, the documents are arranged chronologically. Most of the formal documents exist both in English and in French. The informal documents and national contributions exist in the language in which they were drafted.
A project to release new information on the NPT was launched by the UK, USA and Russia in 2020.
The NATO Archives has published this special collection in support of this effort.
Some records from this collection are available only in French.
NATO publicly disclosed information is available for research and education purposes. Any commercial use requires the written permission of NATO. Please credit the NATO Archives should any documents be used for publication. Guidelines for the proper citation of NATO publicly disclosed information can be found on the NATO Archives website (https://www.nato.int/archives).
- Summary record of private meetings of the Council “Private Records”, 1965-1969; Volume 1; 31 Items; Subject File - Non-Proliferation Treaty
  The NPT was hailed as a landmark treaty, offering a solution to a complicated set of problems facing the world at the time. Prior to the NPT, more than 20 countries were actively seeking nuclear weapons. The NPT created a legal framework defining nuclear weapon possessor and non-possessor states, and providing the context for their cooperation on all three pillars.
  The Treaty is founded on three pillars: non-proliferation; disarmament; and peaceful use of nuclear weapons. Many of the records focus on US-USSR negotiations on Articles I and II of the Treaty regarding stopping the spread of nuclear weapons, and talks about Article III, on safeguards.
  published
  Volume 1 of the collection highlights 31 so called “Private Records,” detailing the views of NATO Allies during informal sessions. This volume is key to understanding the high level positions of many nations on the topic of disarmament, as well as bilateral conversations between NATO members and the USSR.
  Many Private Records include discussion about multiple topics, not all having to do with disarmament or the NPT.
  The documents are arranged chronologically. Private Records are only available in English.
  A project to release new information on the NPT was launched by the UK, USA and Russia in 2020. The NATO Archives has published this special collection in support of this effort.
  NATO publicly disclosed information is available for research and education purposes. Any commercial use requires the written permission of NATO. Please credit the NATO Archives should any documents be used for publication. Guidelines for the proper citation of NATO publicly disclosed information can be found on the NATO Archives website (http://www.nato.int/archives).
  - Summary record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 24th March, 1965 at 10.15 a.m., 1965-03-24; PR(65)13; 3 pages
  - Record of a Private Meeting of the Council held on Wednesday 31st March, 1965, at 10.15 a.m. and 4.30 p.m., 1965-03-31; PR(65)14; 23 pages
  - Summary record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 6th October, 1965 at 10.15 a.m., 1965-10-06; PR(65)47_1; 7 pages
  - Summary record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 20th October 1965 at 10.15 a.m., 1965-10-20; PR(65)49-REDACTED; 16 pages
  - Summary record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 8th December 1965, at 10.15 a.m., 1965-12-08; PR(65)58; 12 pages
  - Record of a Private Meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 12th January, at 10.15 a.m., 1966-01-12; PR(66)01; 8 pages
  - Record of a Private Meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 2nd March, 1966, at 11.00 a.m., 1966-03-02; PR(66)08; 5 pages
  - Summary Record of a Private Meeting of the Council held on Thursday, 29th September, 1966 at 17.00 p.m., 1966-09-29; PR(66)27; 2 pages
  - Summary record of.a Private Meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 12th October, 1966, at 10.15 a.m., 1966-10-12; PR(66)28; 4 pages
  - Summary record of a Private Meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 29th March, 1967, 1967-03-29; PR(67)11; 2 pages
  - RECORD OF A PRIVATE MEETING OF THE COUNCIL IN MINISTERIAL SESSION HELD AT THE KIRCHBERG ON WEDNESDAY, 14TH JUNE, 1967 AT 11.30 A.M., 1967-06-14; PR(67)22; 9 pages
  - Summary record of a Private Meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 28th June, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-06-28; PR(67)24; 7 pages
  - Record of a Private Meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 26th July, 1967, at 10.15 am, 1967-07-26; PR(67)27; 5 pages
  - Summary record of a Private Meeting of Ambassadors held on Wednesday, 23rd August, 1967 at 6.15 p.m., 1967-08-23; PR(67)28; 1 page
  - Record of a Private Meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 27th March, 1968, at 10.15 am, 1968-03-27; PR(68)13-REDACTED; 4 pages
  - Record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 2nd October, 1968, 1968-10-14; PR(68)42; 1 page
  - Record of a private meeting of the Council on Monday, 16th December, 1968, 1968-12-16; PR(68)54; 5 pages
  - Record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 15th December, 1966., 1968-12-18; PR(68)55; 5 pages
  - Record of a private meeting of the Council on Wednesday, 15th January, 1969, at 10.15 a.m., 1969-01-15; PR(69)02; 1 page
  - Private record of a meeting of Ambassadors on Thursday, 23rd January, 1969, at 10.15 a.m., 1969-01-23; PR(69)04; 8 pages
  - Record of a private meeting of the Council held at the Secretary General's residence on Saturday, 1st March, 1969, at 11 a.m., 1969-03-03; PR(69)13; 9 pages
  - Summary record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 12th March, 1969, at 10.15 a.m., 1969-03-25; PR(69)16; 4 pages
  - Summary Record of a private meeting of the Council held on Tuesday, 18th March, 1969, at 10.15 a.m., 1969-03-18; PR(69)17; 12 pages
  - Summary record of a private meeting of the Council held on Thursday, 3rd April, 1969, at 9.45 a.m., 1969-04-03; PR(69)20; 2 pages
  - Informal record of a private meeting of the Council with President Nixon in the State Department Washington, on Friday, 11th April, 1969, at 10.00 a.m., 1969-04-11; PR(69)21; 9 pages
  - Summary record of a private meeting of the DPC held on Thursday, 8th May 1969, at 4.30 p.m., 1969-05-08; PR(69)25; 4 pages
  - Summary record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 14th May, 1969, at 10.15 a.m., 1969-05-14; PR(69)26; 2 pages
  - Summary record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 25th June, 1969, at 10.15 a.m., 1969-07-14; PR(69)31; 13 pages
  - Summary record of a restricted meeting of the Council held on Monday, 30 June 1969, at 9.30 a.m. - Strategic Arms Limitations Talks (SALT), 1969-07-03; PR(69)34_PART_A; 30 pages
  - Summary Record of a private meeting of the Council held on Tuesday, 8th July, 1969 - Strategic Arms Limitations Talks (SALT), 1969-07-08; PR(69)34_PART_B; 29 pages
  - Summary Record of a private meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 16th July, 1969 - Strategic Arms Limitations Talks (SALT), 1969-07-16; PR(69)36_2; 25 pages
  - Compte rendu d'une réunion privée du Conseil tenue le mercredi 27 mars 1968 à 10h15, 1968-03-27; PR(68)13-REDACTED; 4 pages
    Les informations OTAN mises en lecture publique sont accessibles pour des travaux de recherche et d'enseignement. Toute utilisation de ces informations à des fins commerciales nécessite l'autorisation écrite de l'Organisation. Il faut faire état de l'accord des Archives de l'OTAN pour toute utilisation de documents à des fins de publication. Les instructions quant à la manière de bien donner les références des informations OTAN mises en lecture publique peuvent être trouvées sur le site web des Archives de l'OTAN (http://www.nato.int/archives).
  - Compte rendu d'une réunion privée du Conseil tenue le lundi 16 décembre 1968, 1968-12-16; PR(68)54; 5 pages
  - Compte rendu d'une réunion privée du Conseil tenue le mercredi 25 juin 1969 à 10h15, 1969-07-14; PR(69)31; 13 pages
  - Compte rendu d'une réunion privée du Conseil tenue le mercredi 16 juillet 1969 - SALT, 1969-07-16; PR(69)36_2; 25 pages
- Political Affairs Subject File on Proliferation, 1966-1968; Volume 2; 160 Items; Subject File - Non-Proliferation Treaty
  Volume 2 of the collection is a subject file from the Political Affairs division of the NATO International Staff. The Subject File is a collection of relevant records from multiple sources. Subject Files were used by International Staff Divisions to collect relevant information on specific issue. Documents include drafts of the Treaty, letters from Allied delegations, briefing notes and internal opinions on the Treaty process.
  The documents are arranged chronologically. Most documents are only available in one language, but some, like NAC documents, are available in both English and French.
  - EXPLANATORY NOTES TO U.K. DRAFT NON-DISSEMINATION TREATY, 1965-07-05; 1 - UK Letter 05-07-65; 9 pages
  - NON-PROLIFERATION OF NUCLEAR WEAPONS, 1965-07-28; 2 - NE Letter 28-07-65; 8 pages
  - Western Four Working Group Report Concerning Draft Non-Dissemination Treaty, 1965-08-05; 3 - US Letter 05-08-65; 3 pages
  - Wiiliam Foster statemeny on U.S. Non-Proliferation Draft Treaty, 1965-08-31; 5 - Foster Statement 31-08-65; 6 pages
  - STATEMENT BY MR. FOSTER BEFORE THE NATO COUNCIL ON NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1965-09-17; 8 - Foster Statement in NAC 17-09-65; 5 pages
  - USSR DRAFT TREATY CN NON-PROLIFERATICN - Note from which the Canadian Representative spoke at the Political Advisers Committee Meeting of October 12, 1965, 1965-10-14; 9 - CA Comments in POLADS 14-10-65; 3 pages
  - Brief for the Chaiman - Meeting of the Council on Wednesday, 20th October 1965 - Item X - Non-Proliferation in the framework of disarmament, 1965-10-20; 11 - Brief 20-10-1965; 2 pages
  - SPEECH BY THE HONORABLE HARLAN CLEVELAND, U.S. AMBASSADOR TO NATO, DELIVERED BEFORE THE AMERICAN CLUB OF PARIS, ON OCTOBER 21, 1965 - THE OTHER END OF THE TELESCOPE, 1965-10-21; 12 - Cleveland Speech 21-10-65; 10 pages
  - Speech on disarmament questions delivered on October 21 before the First Political Committee of the United Nations General Assembly by the Netherlands State Secretary for Foreign Affairs, Mr. M. van der Stoel., 1965-10-27; 13 - NE Del. Letter No.8198 27-10-65; 8 pages
  - Summary of remarks on the Soviet Draft Treaty on Non-Proliferation of nuclear weapons, made by the Netherlands representative in the Committee of Political Advisers on October 12 and 19, 1965., 1965-10-27; 14 - NE Del. Letter No.8209 27-10-65; 3 pages
  - Disarmament Discussions at the UN General Assembly, 1965-11-12; 15 - GAS(65)198; 3 pages
  - STATEMENT BY AMBASSADOR CLEVELAND IN THE NORTH ATLANTIC COUNCIL, DECEMBER 8, 1965, ON FOSTER-TSARAPKIN DISCUSSIONS COVERING NON-PROLIFERATION AND SECURITY ASSURANCES, 1965-12-08; 16 - Cleveland Statement 08-12-65; 3 pages
  - List of questions given by the Secretary General on disarmament and non-proliferation, 1966-01-25; 17 - List of Questions 25-01-65; 1 page
  - Questions on Non-Proliferation, 1966-02-01; 18 - GAS(66)17; 5 pages
  - ASG Political Affairs reply to SG Questions on Non-Proliferation, 1966-02-02; 19 - DPA(66)37; 1 page
  - Press statement made by Lord Chalfont reported on page 5 of "Le Monde" on 30/51 January - SG Questions on Non-Proliferation, 1966-02-03; 20 - SG(66)58; 2 pages
  - Soviet statement on Non-Proliferation as ENDC Resumes, 1966-02-03; 21 - JP_PM; 3 pages
  - Soviet Statements on Non-Proliferation, 1966-02-04; 22 - GAS(66)19; 1 page
  - Soviet Statements on Non-Proliferation, 1966-02-04; 23 - DPA(66)46; 1 page
  - Nuclear Non-Proliferation, 1966-02-04; 24 - GAS(66)20; 2 pages
  - ASG PA note on memo by Mr. Kühn on non-proliferation, 1966-02-04; 25 - DPA(66)47; 1 page
  - TEXT OF REVISED ARTICLES I, II, AND IV OF THE UNITED STATES DRAFT NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1966-02-05; 26 - US Letter 05-02-66; 5 pages
  - EXPLANATION OF CHANGES IN U.S. DRAFT NONPROLIFERATION TREATY (Memorandum by the U.S. Delegation to the Eighteen Nation Disarmament Conference), 1966-02-07; 27 - US Letter 07-02-66; 7 pages
  - Revised Articles of the US Draft on Non-Proliferation (US note of 7th February, 1966), 1966-02-11; 28 - GAS(66)23; 3 pages
  - Non-proliferation of Nuclear Weapons (Memorandum submitted by the eight non-aligned participants of the Geneva Disarmament Conference on 15th September 1965, 1966-02-18; 29 - GAS(66)25; 3 pages
  - Comments on Mr. Kühn's Memorandum of February 1, 1966, entitled "Questions on Non-Proliferation", 1966-02-25; 30 - JP_MH; 1 page
  - Briefings on questions to be discussed by disarmament experts (28th February - 3rd March) - Part I, 1966-02-28; 31 - Briefing; 6 pages
  - Discussion on Non-Proliferation at the forthcoming APAG meeting, 1966-03-11; 32 - GAS(66)40; 2 pages
  - Address to the WEU-Assembly on November 17th, 1965, by the Netherlands Under-Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, Mr. M. van der Stoel. (extracts), 1966-07-07; 34 - NE Del. Letter No.4948 07-07-66; 5 pages
  - Delegation reaction regarding non-proliferation as possible subject for discussion in the Council, 1966-08-31; 38 - GAS(66)96; 2 pages
  - Discussion of Non-proliferation in Council, 1966-10-06; 40 - DPA(66)276; 4 pages
  - Netherlands proposals for amending the U.S draft non-proliferation treaty, 1966-10-14; 41 - NE Del. Letter No.7151 14-10-66; 2 pages
  - US Draft Treaty to prevent the spread of Nuclear Weapons, 1966-10-18; 42 - US letter 18-10-66; 5 pages
  - Council Agenda, 19th October 1966 - Item II - Non-proliferation, 1966-10-18; 43 - DPA(66)286; 2 pages
  - Oral explanation to the Netherlands proposals for amending the American draft non-proliferatiion treaty, 1966-10-19; 44 - NE Statement 19-10-66; 1 page
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 19th October 1966 at 10.15 a.m., 1966-10-24; 45 - C-R(66)55; 3 pages
  - Restricted Annex to summary record of a meeting of the Council held on Wednesday, 19th October, 1966 at 10.15 a.m. - NON-PROLIFERATION, 1966-11-02; 47 - C-R(66)55 ANNEX; 14 pages
  - REVISED SUMMARY OF INTERPRETATIONS OF NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY (NPT), 1966-00-00; 49 - Revised Text of NPT; 10 pages
  - Submission of note on non-proliferation by Mr. Kühn, 1967-01-16; 50 - RS(67)6; 5 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Tuesday, 17th January, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-01-30; 51 - C-R(67)2; 15 pages
  - New U.S. Draft for a Non-proliferation Treaty, 1967-01-26; 54 - RS(67)20; 6 pages
  - New United States Draft for a Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1967-01-31; 55 - DPA(67)14; 2 pages
  - Items for discussion at the forthcoming meeting of the Political Advisers’ Committee with disarmament experts, 1967-02-01; 56 - UK Letter 01-02-1967; 1 page
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 1st February, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-02-13; 58 - C-R(67)5; 24 pages
  - Issues raised in Councll Discussion of Non-Proliferation Treaty Draft, 1967-02-07; 61 - DPA(67)21; 5 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 8th February, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-02-17; 63 - C-R(67)7; 24 pages
  - Statement made by Mr. Oncken in today's Council Meeting during the discussion of the Draft Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1967-02-08; 65 - 20-10-5_67; 4 pages
  - NON-PROLIFERATION OF NUCLEAR WEAPONS - STATEMENT BY THE PORTUGUESE DELEGATION, 1967-02-13; 66 - PO(67)87; 3 pages
  - The new U.S. draft Article III of a non-proliferation treaty concerning "safeguards", 1967-02-13; 68 - RS(67)32; 5 pages
  - Translation from "Die Welt" of an article on Non-Proliferation and the NATO Treaty, 1967-02-14; 69 - RS(67)34; 5 pages
  - Further comments on U.S. draft Article III of a non-proliferation treaty concerning "safeguards", 1967-02-20; 70 - RS(67)40; 6 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Oouncil held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 22nd February, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-03-01; 73 - C-R(67)9; 18 pages
  - DRAFT TEXT OF NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1967-03-04; 76 - ZA 5-11-67 ZU IIB - 419/67; 10 pages
  - REVISED TEXT OF DRAFT NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1967-03-04; 77 - Revised text of NPT; 10 pages
  - German Government considerations with regard to certain aspects of the treaty, 1967-03-20; 79 - GE Del. 20-10-5_1011_67; 9 pages
  - Recent Developments Concerning the Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1967-03-22; 80 - DPA(67)79; 8 pages
  - US Contribution to the Council discussion of Non-Proliiferation April 4, 1967-04-03; 81 - Revised Text of Draft NPT; 11 pages
  - REVISED BRIEF FOR THE CHAIRMAN MEETING OF THE COUNCIL ON TUESDAY, 4th APBIL, 1967 - ITEM II - DISARMAMENT, 1967-04-03; 82 - DPA(67)86; 1 page
  - NAC MEETING APRIL 4, 1967 - REMARKS BY WILLIAM C. FOSTER, DIRECTOR OF THE UNITED STATES ARMS CONTROL AND DISARMAMENT AGENCY, 1967-04-04; 83 - Statement by Mr. Foster; 10 pages
  - Statement made by the German Permanent Representative at the Council Meeting on 4 April 1967, 1967-04-05; 84 - GE Del. 20-10-5_1217_67 04-04-67; 11 pages
  - Non-proliferation - Essential points of a statement made by the Netherlands Permanent Representative at the Oounoil meeting on April 12, 1967, 1967-04-13; 86 - NE Del. Letter No.2315; 4 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Oouncil held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 12th April, 1967 at 10.15 a.m., 1967-04-26; 87 - C-R(67)17; 32 pages
  - Lord Chalfont statement re. the Safeguards Article of the proposed Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1967-04-19; 89 - Cleveland Statement 19-04-67; 3 pages
  - REDRAFT OF POSSIBLE NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY FORMULATIONS, 1967-04-17; 90 - Redraft of NPT Formulations; 12 pages
  - Statement by Gen. E.L.M. Burns at NAC Meeting April 20, 1967 on draft Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1967-04-20; 91 - Statement by Gen. Burns 20-04-67; 5 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Thursday, 20th April, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-05-09; 92 - C-R(67)18; 23 pages
  - STATEMENT BY AMBASSADOR CLEVELAND ON NON-PROLIFERATION, 1967-05-03; 93 - Statement by Cleveland 03-05-67; 19 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Friday, 5th May, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-05-17; 94 - C-R(67)20; 10 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 10th May, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-05-25; 95 - C-R(67)21; 21 pages
  - TALKING POINTS ON NPT FOR NAC, May 17, 1967-05-17; 96 - Talking Points on NPT; 4 pages
  - Summary Record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 17th May, 1967, at 10.15 a.m. and 3.30 p.m., 1967-05-07; 97 - C-R(67)22; 40 pages
  - STATEMENT TO NAC MAY 24, 1967 by Ambassador Harlan Cleveland, 1967-05-24; 98 - Cleveland Statement 24-05-67; 20 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 24th May, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-05-09; 99 - C-R(67)23; 22 pages
  - Non-Proliferation Treaty: Amendments, 1967-05-31; 100 - NPT Amendments 31-05-67; 3 pages
  - DRAFT NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1967-06-11; 101 - Draft NPT 11-06-67; 10 pages
  - NEW US DRAFT FOR NON-PROLIFERATION TREATY, 1967-06-12; 102 - Letter from ASG PA to SG 12-06-67; 3 pages
  - AMBASSADOR CLEVELAND'S STATEMENT ON NON-PROLIFERATION TO PERMANENT REPRESENTATIVES, 1967-06-21; 103 - Cleveland Statement 21-06-67; 2 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 4th July, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-07-20; 104 - C-R(67)31; 9 pages
  - STATEMENT BY AMBASSADOR FOSTER TO BE MADE IN WASHINGTON 1200 PM, AUGUST 11, 1967, 1967-08-11; 105 - Statement by Foster 11-08-67; 3 pages
  - Update of US discussions with the Soviets on Article III, 1967-08-19; 106 - US Letter 19-08-67; 4 pages
  - Classification downgrade for Draft of tbe Non-Proliferation Treaty distributed August 24, 1967-08-28; 107 - US Del. Aide Memoire 28-08-1967; 2 pages
  - STATEMENT BY AMBASSADOR CLEVELAND TO THE COUNCIL ON NON-PROLIFERATION, 1967-09-06; 108 - Clevelands Statement 06-09-67; 28 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 6th September, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-09-18; 109 - C-R(67)36; 26 pages
  - New Proposals for Article III of the Non-Prollferation Treaty, 1967-09-07; 110 - RS(67)100; 4 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 13th September, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-09-29; 111 - C-R(67)38; 23 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 20th September, 1967, at 10.15 a.m., 1967-10-02; 112 - C-R(67)39; 31 pages
  - Summary record of a meeting of the Council held at the Permanent Headquarters, Paris, 16e., on Wednesday, 26th September, 1967, at 9.30 a.m., 1967-10-16; 113 - C-R(67)40; 20 pages